We just took a look at enterprise environmental factors organizational process assets follow E-F a lot
of times we'll see a process has for his inputs enterprise environmental factors and organizational
process assets are O.P. organizational process assets or resources within an organization.
There are things that you can leverage things that are been researched and created for you or the things
that can be interviewed like people historical information is one of your best opaque because historical
information has proven information its past experiences that you can leverage to manage your current
project.
So a great example of this would be we treat historical information like a template.
A lot of times we think of a template as a form that has been created for us that we fill out.
And certainly that's a template like a scope template or a charter template but a template can also
be that we take a prior project.
For example we could take the quality management plan from a prior project and just adapt it to our
current project.
Similar or we can take the scope from a similar project that we don't have to write it from scratch
every time.
Work smart it will take something similar and use that as a template so that we can save time and have
historical information that's been proven.
So historical information is one of our best organizational process assets.
We also have some common Opas you should be familiar with standards policies and organizational procedures.
Well a lot of times people say wait a minute policies were also enterprise environmental factors.
How can they be both.
What policies can be both standards can be both that it's not always being enterprise environmental
factors are always things that constrain you.
They can also be things that have been created for you and that have been established for uniformity.
So policies could be how changes are allowed to come into the project or how you must do cost estimating
or time estimating duration estimating how people are allowed to come onto your project or communicate
directly with the project team.
So those could be policies and standards as well.
So yes there are enterprise environmental factors things that you must follow.
But an old P.A. can also be things that help you.
So I like to think of enterprise environmental factors are things that restrict your choices.
Almost like a constraint because you must do are things that help you have been created for you to make
your project more successful or to try to massage the conditions to allow your project to be more successful.
Your organization might have some standardized guidelines or performance measurements that you have
to adhere to.
So like you can't be too much over cost or too much below cost or off schedule too much or you can't
leave a phase until you have this level of performance or this level of accuracy you might have templates
as they just mentioned for project documents like a scope template or a charter template and that we
can use historical information for that.
And you might have some guidelines for adapting project management processes.
So what this means is you could look at those 49 project management processes in your organization you
can say OK this is how we as an organization will define scope.
This is how we create the work breakdown structure how everyone does it the same way or how we do quality
control or how we do stakeholder engagement.
So just some guidelines for how do you do those processes in your organization.
There's not a universal way to do every process because every organization and every project is different.
So I get questions sometimes you know email from folks that they'll ask if you have a template for a
project chart or I could use.
Do you have a template for a risk management plan.
Well yes but no it's not really appropriate for you because where I created those was a totally different
organization and the risk and the scope and the concerns of that organization were unique to that company.
But it's probably totally different from your company.
Now there are forms and templates in fact PMI has a whole book on forms and templates but you can't
just take those and there you go and shove it into your project.
They have to be adapted and created for your organization.
So this is the idea here with these old days that it's adapting the project management processes.
But for your projects for your organization there's not a one size fits all when it comes to Opas and
these processes some common Opas we should be familiar with financial controls for purchasing So again
forms and processes and workflow accounting codes that are unique to your organization.
How you do procurement where you are communication requirements things like standard forms procedures
reports.
Those are communication requirements that we have processes for project activities of change control
how you do change control in your organization how do you close out the project.
What about communications financial controls in risk control procedures.
So those are all open.
So those have been established or adapted for what's best in your organization and then project closing
So how do you do acceptance and sign off.
You have a certificate of completion or is there a sign off that the scope's been done.
So how do you close out the project.
How does the customer validate the product.
So is there an operational transfer.
And you have something written that the project is now closed and this is now part of production or
operations or is it kind of a non event.
So what's the norm for your organization and then evaluations so think about evaluations of the project
of the product of your project team.
Some assessments there that those could be an opiate.
We'll see organizational process assets a lot.
It's an input to a lot of our 40 processes and it typically goes with EDF that those two go together.
We'll also see throughout our examination of the outputs of a process is that O.P. a it enterprise environmental
factors are often updated to reflect what's happened in the project All right good job I'll see you
in the next lecture.